Wow, Dad, this is delicious.
爸，這個也太好吃了吧
You like it?
妳喜歡嗎？
That's braised pork. It's new on the menu.
這個是燉小排，是新的菜式
It's soft and melts in my mouth.
簡直是入口即化啊
It's very mild, but it has a deep flavor.
雖然味道不重，但是很有層次呢
Mr. Soma, you're the only one that can word it so well.
也只有相馬你能形容得那麼細緻了
I said it well too.
我也形容得很好啊
Your restaurant has good ratings on gourmet sites.
你的居酒屋在美食網站上 評分可是很高的哦
-This restaurant is listed on that site? -Yes.
-網站上有我們店嗎？ -有啊
-I've never seen it before. -Check it out.
-我都沒看過呢 -現在看看
Hanasaki.
花咲
There it is.
就是這個
You have 4.21 stars. That's really good.
4.21顆星，好厲害啊
Really?
是嗎？
Five is the highest rating you can get, so anything over four is very good.
滿分是五顆星 四星以上已經是很高的評價了
"The owner runs the restaurant by himself, and makes mild, yet unforgettable dishes.
“這家店由老闆一人經營 菜餚味道溫和，但令人難忘
It makes you want to come back for more. Five stars."
是讓人想再次光顧的店，五顆星
"Comfortable interior.
店內氛圍舒適安心
You must try the sashimi and stew.
一定要試試刺身和燉肉
You can also enjoy the downtown atmosphere.
能好好享受街區的風情
-However…" -However?
-可是…” -可是？
"The owner was offering free appetizers to the female customers,
“老闆只給女性顧客贈送小菜
but he didn't offer any to us older men. So we give it three stars."
我們這些大叔什麼都沒有 很遺憾，所以給三顆星”
Dad…
爸
I've never done such a thing.
我絕沒有做過這種事情哦
I serve all customers equally.
我對所有顧客都是平等的
In fact, I just saw you giving free stewed beef tendons to a female customer.
這麼一說，你剛才送了盤牛筋魚凍 給一位女性顧客呢
I just had an extra plate.
那個只是剛好多出來的
You didn't give it to us.
你也沒給我們啊
Yes. I was wondering why.
是啊，我還在想為什麼呢
But you are like my family.
一家人幹嘛計較這個呢？
I'm sorry.
對不起
NAME: FOX I WILL DESTROY THAT BANK TOMORROW
（狐狸：我明天會毀掉銀行）
WHICH BANK?
（無名氏：哪間銀行）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK TOYOSU BRANCH
（狐狸：東京第一銀行豐洲分行）
Destroy the bank?
毀掉銀行？
It was an anonymous post on a message board,
這是一個匿名論壇裡的內容
so it could very well be a prank.
雖然有可能是惡作劇
It's so scary.
但還是很擔心啊
We often see this type of death threat on the internet,
這種線上的犯罪預告很常見
but I never thought it would happen to us.
但沒想到會發生在我們銀行
Yes. So I want you to go and check out the Toyosu Branch.
是啊，所以我想請你們去看看 豐州分行的情況
Just to be safe.
以防萬一吧
I wonder why this person used Fox as their username?
為什麼這個人的網名是狐狸呢？
Yeah, it's a little creepy.
是啊，感覺有點不吉利
Don't let it bother you.
別想太多啦
TOYOSU BRANCH
（豐洲分行）
What is it?
怎麼了？
I feel like the Fox is watching us.
我覺得那個狐狸在盯著我們呢
That's the Inari Shrine.
是稻荷神社啦
I'm sorry to drag you from headquarters for something like this.
抱歉 這麼點小事還要麻煩總部的人來
No.
不會
It's no problem.
您客氣了
But Branch Inspection must have lots of time to spare…
這種線上留言還一一查看
DEPUTY BRANCH MANAGER HIDEO NAKANO
（副經理，中野秀夫）
…since you're responding to internet messages like these.
分行稽核班一定很閒吧？
Well, they came to help us so we should be appreciative.
好了，他們是來幫忙我們的 我們應該要感恩才對
Okay.
是
By the way, are there any problems with
分行最近與客戶
customers or loan clients at this bank?
或融資夥伴之間有過什麼糾紛嗎？
Of course not.
當然沒有了
The Toyosu Branch has the least complaints from customers.
豐州分行沒什麼客戶投訴這件事
Didn't you know that?
你們不知道嗎？
Yes, I'm aware of that. I asked just in case.
這個我知道，只是以防萬一問問而已
Can you let us watch over the sales floor and the ATM corner today?
那我們今天能不能 巡查營業樓層和提款機區域？
No, you can't.
不行
The customers will get wary if they see you wandering around.
你們在那邊走來走去 顧客會覺得很可疑的
Then what if we stand there as an attendant?
那如果我們 是作為引導人員站在那裡呢？
That's not necessary.
沒這個必要
Let them do it, Nakano.
讓他們去吧，中野
If the branch manager says so.
三枝經理都這麼說了，那好吧
But please don't disturb our business.
不過，請不要妨礙我們的業務
-Yes. -Of course.
-是 -當然了
I'm sure nothing will happen.
我不認為會發生什麼事
Ms. Hanasaki, I'm sorry for making you take on such a dangerous job.
不過，讓花咲小姐妳一個女生 做這麼危險的工作，真是抱歉呢
Oh, no problem at all. I am okay--
哪裡，我沒關係的，我…
She is okay. Hanasaki is very tough.
沒事的，花咲她強壯得很
I think she is stronger than me.
說不定比我還強呢
Good luck.
拜託你們了
Yes.
好的
The branch manager is really nice.
三枝經理真親切啊
No one has ever worried about me before.
以前都沒人那樣關懷過我呢
He was so calm.
他確實很溫厚
It's surprising for someone in the Shindo faction.
這樣的人居然是真藤派的
Branch Manager Saegusa is in the Shindo faction?
三枝經理是真藤派的嗎？
Didn't I tell you?
我沒說過嗎？
I didn't expect that.
太意外了吧
I can understand it if that Deputy Branch Manager was in the Shindo faction.
要是那個討人厭的副經理是真藤派的 我還看得出來
That's enough. Let's go.
又亂說話了，走吧
Hanasaki.
花咲
You're scowling.
妳的表情太可怕了
Sorry, I was concentrating on the Fox, so I couldn't resist.
抱歉，我一直想著要找出狐狸 一時不小心
You can never resist.
妳什麼時候小心了？
How about this?
那這樣呢？
-Fox! -What?
-狐狸 -什麼？
"Sad Fox."
《悲傷的狐狸》
This is nothing but a picture book.
這只是一本繪本啦
-I know. -Fox!
-我知道啊 -狐狸
Where is the Fox?
狐狸在哪？
Over there!
在那邊
-Fox… -It's cute.
-狐狸 -好可愛啊
I can't get the Fox out of my mind.
搞得我滿腦子都是狐狸
Everything is balanced. Thank you for your hard work.
今天的帳沒問題，辛苦你們了
Thank you.
-辛苦了
I'm glad nothing happened.
平安無事，真是太好了
That message was a prank, just as we expected.
那個留言果然只是惡作劇啊
I'm so relieved that I'm getting hungry.
心情放鬆了，肚子也跟著餓了
Hey, we didn't eat lunch today.
我們今天都沒吃午餐呢
You are right.
是啊
-Let's eat something on our way back. -Sounds good.
-先吃點東西再回家吧 -好主意
How about Fox Noodle to end this day?
就以狐狸烏龍麵結束這一天吧
No way.
不要啦
Please evacuate immediately.
請立即疏散
-Go check it out. -Yes!
-去看看發生什麼事 -是
-Hanasaki! -Yes.
-花咲
Please evacuate immediately.
請立即疏散
FIRE ALARM
（發生火災）
The garbage room.
是垃圾房
Where is it?
在這裡
-Around that corner. -Yes.
-就在那邊 -是
There's smoke.
有煙
-We need the key. -Here.
-鑰匙呢？ -這裡
-Fire extinguisher! -Right here!
-滅火器呢？ -來了
Please step back.
請後退
ATM CORNER
（提款機區域）
Why did the fire break out in there?
為什麼那種地方會著火啊？
How did this happen?
怎麼會這樣？
The silver lining is that we caught it early on.
幸好我們及時控制住了火勢
But this is a problem.
但還是很麻煩啊
Did Fox set the fire?
是狐狸縱火的嗎？
It's possible.
有可能
Excuse me.
打擾了
I am Kadokura of the Toyosu police station.
我是豐州警局的門倉
-I am Saito. -Did you find anything?
-我是齋藤 -你們查到什麼了嗎？
The garbage collected at the ATM corner was the source of fire.
從提款機區域收集到的垃圾裡 找到了火災的源頭
ATM?
提款機？
The suspect placed a timed ignition advice
犯人將一個定時引燃裝置
in the garbage by the ATM corner.
扔到了提款機區域的垃圾桶
It ignited after it was collected into the garbage room?
然後垃圾被送到了垃圾房 裝置就被引燃了？
Right.
沒錯
Can I check the footage from the security camera?
能讓我們看看監視影像嗎？
-Yes. -This way, please.
-好的 -這邊請
There is no one suspicious.
沒有發現可疑人物呢
Not yet.
還沒發現
What is it?
怎麼了？
There's a deposit of one yen to a donation account.
這裡有一筆匯款 給募捐的帳戶匯了一日元
-One yen? -Please check the name.
-一日元？ -你看匯款人的名字
Cash transfer at 12:50 p.m. The remitter is…
12點50分，現金匯款，匯款人…
I will punish the rotten bank.
“我要懲罰這腐敗的銀行
Fox.
狐狸”
Fox?
狐狸？
Do you know about this Fox?
你們認識這個狐狸？
There was a message on the internet threatening to destroy the Toyosu Branch.
其實，有人在網路上留言說 要毀掉豐州分行
That message was posted under the username Fox.
上傳這則留言的人網名是狐狸
-Who is this? -Check the video.
-那是誰呢？ -看看監視影像
Yes.
是
12:50…
12點50分
It's him.
就是他
We can't see his face.
看不到臉啊
It seems to be a young man around 20 years old.
看起來是個20歲左右的年輕男子
-Is that the ignition device? -Maybe.
-這個就是引燃裝置嗎？ -應該是
This is ridiculous.
開什麼玩笑？
Can you identify him?
能確認身分嗎？
No, because this is a cash transfer.
不能，這是現金匯款
How did he get his name to be printed like this?
但是，怎麼能打印出這樣的名字呢？
When cash is transferred at the ATM,
用提款機匯入現金的時候
the remitter enters their own name.
匯款人是自行輸入姓名的
It can be anything within 40 characters.
能夠任意輸入40字以內的內容
Branch Inspection!
分行稽核班！
You didn't notice that a crime was happening right in front of you?
這起犯罪就在你們眼前發生 你們都沒察覺嗎？
You were keeping watch to prevent this from happening.
你們那樣監視 不就是為了預防這種事嗎？
-I am sorry. -Sorry.
-非常抱歉 -對不起
This is all your fault, Branch Inspection.
這都是你們分行稽核班的責任
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花咲居酒屋）
Of course, I feel bad that we couldn't catch the culprit.
當然了，沒當場發現犯人是我們失誤
But I don't think we deserved to be yelled at like that.
但不至於被罵成那樣吧
He looked like an ordinary young man,
那個人看起來只是個普通的年輕人
and it's natural to put garbage
只是扔個垃圾而已
in the garbage can, so no one would think that it's suspicious.
這麼常見的動作，誰會覺得可疑啊？
The branch manager suddenly changed his attitude once something happened.
那個三枝經理一出事就突然變了個人
He has two very different sides to him, that's for sure.
他確實是個表裡不一的雙面人呢
I want to solve this case and teach that branch manager a lesson.
真想把這件事情解決 給那個三枝經理點顏色瞧瞧
Mai, I heard that there was a fire at your bank.
小舞，聽說你們銀行著火了
-How did you know? -I saw it on TV.
-你怎麼知道的？ -新聞播了啊
They said it was arson. Is that true?
說是人為縱火呢，沒事吧？
It was okay because it was caught before it escalated.
在火勢變嚴重前就控制住了 所以沒什麼事
How scary.
好危險啊
It would be great if it ends here.
要是這樣結束就好了
What's wrong? You both look so tired.
你們兩個怎麼回事？一臉鬱悶的
There's a lot going on.
說不清呢
Eat this and cheer up. It's on me.
那請你吃這個，打起精神吧
Thank you.
謝謝
This is new on the menu. Crown daisy and daikon fox salad.
這是我們的新菜色 春菊蘿蔔狐狸沙拉
Fox?
狐狸？
It's called Fox?
狐狸嗎？
ARSON ATTACK AT TOKYO DAIICHI BANK'S TOYOSU BRANCH
（東京第一銀行豐洲分行縱火案）
NAME: FOX
（名字：狐狸）
NEVER FORGIVE TOKYO DAIICHI BANK TOYOSU BRANCH
（無法原諒東京第一銀行豐洲分行）
PUNISH BRANCH MANAGER SAEGUSA
（懲罰分行經理三枝）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK TOYOSU BRANCH
（東京第一銀行豐洲分行）
SMALL FIRE AT TOKYO DAIICHI BANK POSSIBLY ARSON
（東京第一銀行人為縱火）
Did you see the new post by the arsonist?
你們看到縱火犯的最新留言了嗎？
I did. He mentioned the name of the branch manager.
看了，這次提到經理的名字了呢
How scary.
好可怕啊
PUNISH BRANCH MANAGER SAEGUSA
（懲罰分行經理三枝）
Why is he mentioning my name?
為什麼會提到我的名字？
This is Saegusa.
是，我是三枝
Good morning, Mr. Kodama.
早安，兒玉次長
Is it just me or is he glaring at us?
他好像在盯著我們啊
He's trying to tell us that this is all our fault.
應該是想說都是我們的錯吧
Executive Director Shindo, I am sorry for troubling you.
真藤常務 對於這次引起的騷動，我很抱歉
-Don't say unnecessary things. -I know.
-妳可別說多餘的話啊 -知道了
Explain this to me.
麻煩你解釋一下這是怎麼回事
Yes.
是
Someone placed a timed ignition device
昨天12點50分 有人將一個引燃裝置
into the garbage can at 12:50 p.m. yesterday.
扔進了提款機區域的垃圾桶裡
It's believed to have ignited in the garbage collection room.
這個應該就是垃圾房起火的原因
The criminal gave prior notice of this crime by posting it on the internet, yes?
罪犯事前在網路論壇上 留下了犯罪預告，是嗎？
Well… he implied that he would.
他暗示了會這麼做
What does the culprit want?
那罪犯的目的是什麼？
We don't know.
不知道
Why is he targeting the Toyosu Branch?
那他為什麼會針對豐州分行呢？
Do you have any problems with customers that went bankrupt?
你們是不是 跟破產的客戶有過什麼糾紛？
-No, we do not. -Nothing.
-沒有過這樣的事 -沒有
-Excuse me. -Huh?
-那個… -嗯？
The culprit who calls himself Fox, mentioned
化名為狐狸的那位犯人
Branch Manager Saegusa by name on yesterday's post.
在昨晚的留言提到了三枝經理的名字
Why was that?
那是為什麼呢？
That's my question.
我正想問這個呢
I think the suspect holds a grudge, not against the Toyosu Branch,
我認為犯人要報復的不是豐州分行
but against Branch Manager Saegusa.
而是三枝經理
Are you saying
妳的意思是…
that someone has a personal grudge against me?
有人對我懷恨在心嗎？
Stop being so rude.
妳也太失禮了吧？
I'm sorry.
對不起
It doesn't matter whether the target is the bank or the branch manager.
目標是銀行還是經理並不重要
In any case, the public will think that Tokyo Daiichi Bank is the target.
因為無論如何 大衆都會認為目標是東京第一銀行
There are two things that we should do right now.
我們現在要做的事情有兩件
Cooperate with police to arrest the suspect
第一，與警方合作，逮捕嫌犯
and wrap up this case as soon as possible.
儘快解決這件事
We must stop this case from destroying our bank's credibility.
第二，防止這件事損害銀行的信用
Therefore, we need to conduct an internal investigation.
因此，我們必須進行內部調查
There may be information that can't be publicized.
說不定有些資訊不能對外洩露
Let's get Branch Inspection to investigate.
那就讓分行稽核班進行調查吧
No. You should be in charge, Kodama.
不，這次由兒玉來負責
Why is that?
為什麼？
Branch Inspection overlooked the criminal yesterday.
分行稽核班 昨天不是沒察覺到犯人嗎？
I am sorry.
十分抱歉
First of all, I will make a list of customers from the Toyosu Branch
首先，我會整理一個清單 列明過去五年內
that have gone bankrupt in the last five years--
豐州分行的破產企業客戶…
Mr. Doujima.
堂島專務
I think Branch Inspection would be ideal for this case.
我覺得還是交給分行稽核班解決吧
They have solved many problems at different branches.
他們已經解決了 各分行大大小小的問題
We should rely on them for a serious case such as this.
這次那麼嚴重的事件 我們更應該交給他們
But they made a mistake.
但他們有過失誤了
If someone on your side is in charge,
要是把這件事交給你的人去處理
things can be covered up before it's reported to me.
我可能還沒收到報告 事情就被暗中解決了
I wouldn't do such a thing.
我絕對不會這麼做的
I understand.
我知道了
I want you to get the job done this time.
那你們這次一定要把事情辦好
This is your last chance.
不准再失敗了
-Yes.
-是
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
MEETING RECORD
（會面記錄）
I can't find anything just by looking at the numbers on the credit files.
只是看這些信用檔案裡的數據 怎麼會有線索啊？
I agree.
就是說啊
This doesn't record people's feelings.
這裡又沒有記載人的感情
They know what caused the fire.
知道起火原因了
We got a report from the police.
這是警方的報告
Apparently, the fire was set using alkali metal.
好像是用鹼金屬起的火
Alkali metal?
鹼金屬？
It ignites once it comes into contact with air.
鹼金屬只要接觸到空氣就會起火
CHEMICAL COMPOUND OF ALKALI METAL
（鹼金屬的化學合成物）
The culprit put a piece of that meal in a plastic bag with preservative solution,
犯人將鹼金屬的碎片 跟保存液一起放入塑膠袋裡
poked a small hole in it and put it in the garbage can.
然後在塑膠袋上戳了一個小孔 再扔進垃圾箱裡
The preservative solution gradually leaked,
這樣保存液會漸漸漏出來
and the alkali metal ignited when it came into contact with air.
等到鹼金屬和空氣一接觸就會著火
I see.
原來如此
Is it easy to obtain that alkali metal?
鹼金屬是很容易弄到手的東西嗎？
No. It is usually unavailable to the general public.
不，一般人是很難接觸到的
So the culprit must be someone who has a way to obtain it.
犯人很可能是 能夠把那種東西弄到手的人
Then the culprit must be someone who is or was working
所以犯人應該是某家
for a company that handles alkali metal.
能接觸到鹼金屬的公司的 現任或前任員工
What kind of company is that?
那會是什麼公司呢？
A battery factory, university laboratory,
電池製造工廠、大學研究所
a company that processes glass, and so on.
或者是玻璃製造加工的公司等等
Glass… there was a company among these files that handles glass.
玻璃公司？ 這些檔案裡有一家玻璃公司呢
-Tokita Glass. -Here it is.
-時田玻璃公司 -找到了
-What kind of company was that? -Yes.
-這公司怎麼了？ -是
They seemed to have maintained a stable performance
他們的業績一直都很穩定
but failed to expand their business and went bankrupt a year ago.
卻因為擴大經營失敗 在一年前破產了
How about debt?
債務呢？
No debt.
沒有債務
All of their debts were settled.
全部都還清了
Okay. Let's go to the Toyosu Branch and get some details.
好，我們去豐州分行問問看吧
Okay.
好的
Tokita Glass?
時田玻璃公司？
We would like to know the details that led to their bankruptcy.
我們想要知道這家公司破產的細節
For example, did you have problems with this company?
比如說 你們有沒有跟他們起過爭執？
Do you think the manager is calm when his company goes bankrupt?
妳覺得破產的時候 他們還會心平氣和嗎？
They often become emotional and end up screaming and cursing at us.
通常都是激動不已 把我們罵得狗血淋頭啊
I can't be a banker if I let something like that bother me.
要是對那種事都在意的話 我們怎麼工作？
I understand.
是這樣沒錯
-But if you remember anything-- -I don't remember anything.
-但你記不記得… -我都說不記得了
It's a waste of time to look into this. Go back to your office.
打聽這種事簡直是浪費時間 你們回去吧
BRANCH MANAGER'S OFFICE
（分行經理辦公室）
He's so suspicious.
他很可疑呢
Yes. He's hiding something.
是啊，好像在隱瞞什麼
Let's ask the Finance Department.
我們去問問融資課的人吧
Don't let him find out.
不過，不能被他知道
Okay.
是
Tokita Glass?
時田玻璃？
That can't be…
不會吧？
Damn it!
可惡
I was in charge of Tokita Glass.
我就是時田玻璃的負責人
But I don't know much about the details.
不過，我也不是很清楚詳細的情況
So the actual negotiation was done by your boss.
所以實際的交易往來 都是你的上司進行的嗎？
Yes. It was Branch Manager Saegusa.
對，是由三枝經理負責的
Why was that?
三枝經理？
It was when he was trying really hard to improve the numbers at this branch,
那時候他正好在拼命提高分行業績
so he personally went to Tokita Glass to offer the loan.
所以就親自負責了時田玻璃的融資
It seems like they paid off the loan before they went bankrupt.
對方好像在破產前 就付清了所有貸款金額
You don't know anything about that either?
這件事你也不清楚嗎？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
But I heard the other banks couldn't get their loans recovered, so I'm sure
但我聽說其他銀行 都沒辦法回收他們的融資
our branch manager aggressively demanded it back.
所以，三枝經理應該是強制回收的
I see.
原來如此
We want to talk with someone from Tokita Glass.
我們想跟時田玻璃的人談一談
The president and his son moved to an apartment after they went bankrupt.
社長和他的兒子 在破產之後搬到了公寓
The senior executive director moved to his hometown, Iwate.
他們的專務董事好像回到了故鄉岩手
Do you have their contact information?
你有他們的聯繫方式嗎？
PRESIDENT KIICHIRO TOKITA
（時田紀一郎社長）
President Tokita's house should be around here.
時田社長的家應該在這附近吧？
There it is. Shiomi Corp.
那邊，潮見公寓
Maybe they're out.
可能出去了
Excuse me. Does Mr. Tokita live here?
不好意思 請問這裡是時田先生的家嗎？
-Yes. -We are from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
-是的 -我們是東京第一銀行的職員
We'd like to talk to Mr. Kiichiro Tokita.
有事想找時田紀一郎先生談談
He passed away recently.
他前一陣子過世了
It was about a month ago.
大約是一個月前吧？
I guess he had a chronic heart disease.
他心臟本來就不好
But he was a president, right?
以前還是社長呢
I heard he had a hard time because his company went bankrupt.
公司破產之後，應該吃了不少苦吧？
Apparently, that took a toll on him and worsened his condition.
好像是因為這件事操心過度 才加重了他的病情
Oh, really…
這樣啊
I heard that his son lives here, too.
那跟他一起生活的兒子呢？
I haven't seen him recently.
最近都沒看到他呢
According to rumors, he's a recluse.
聽說他很孤僻，老是足不出戶
Do you know how old his son is?
他兒子多大了？
I remember hearing that he had a Coming-of-age ceremony last year.
我好像聽別人說過 他去年參加了成人儀式
May I go now?
我可以走了嗎？
Sure. Thank you for your time.
不好意思，耽誤妳那麼久
Thank you very much.
謝謝妳
The Fox we saw on the security footage seemed to be around 20 years old.
監視器拍到的狐狸 看起來是20歲左右的男性
Yes.
是啊
His son's name is Tsuneo, huh?
他兒子的名字叫恒夫啊
Yes.
嗯
Tsuneo…
恒夫
-Fox! -Again?
-狐狸！ -妳又來了
Look here, Mr. Soma.
相馬，你看
What is it?
怎麼了？
Read this vertically.
你豎著讀一下
F… ox.
“紀恒”
-Fox? -Yes.
-跟狐狸同音 -是的
Is Tsuneo Tokita the Fox?
時田恒夫就是狐狸？
It is possible.
應該是
But why?
可是，為什麼呢？
The president of Tokita Glass died,
時田玻璃的社長死了
and his son holds a grudge against Branch Manager Saegusa.
而他兒子怨恨三枝經理
There might have been something behind the bankruptcy.
破產事件的背後或許有什麼隱情
NAME: FOX
（名字：狐狸）
I WILL NEVER STOP UNTIL BRANCH MANAGER SAEGUSA IS PUNISHED
（分行經理三枝得到懲罰之前 我是不會收手的）
Have you seen this young man?
請問你見過這個年輕人嗎？
I know a man who looks similar.
我認識一個人很像他
The police are searching for Tsuneo Tokita as the suspect.
警方正在通緝重要嫌疑人時田恒夫
I see.
這樣啊
He worked for Tokita Glass after he graduated high school.
據說他從高中畢業之後 就在時田玻璃公司工作了
But he became a recluse after the bankruptcy,
公司破產之後 他就常常把自己關在家裡
and he wasn't working either.
也沒有工作
He probably hates and blames the bank
公司破產、父親死亡
for the bankruptcy and his father's death.
他認為這都是銀行的錯 所以心生怨恨吧？
We will have to leave the rest to the police.
剩下的就交給警方處理
You did a good job.
辛苦你們了
What's wrong, Hanasaki?
怎麼了，花咲？
I've been thinking about what his objective is for doing this.
我一直在想他的目的到底是什麼
He posted a message saying, "Punish Branch Manager Saegusa."
他在網路上留言說 “要制裁三枝經理”
But I don't think he's planning to actually cause him harm.
但我不認為他是想要傷害三枝經理
What do you think he wants?
那妳覺得他的目的是什麼？
There might be something that he wants the public to know about.
他可能有什麼想讓大衆知道的事
I think he created this fuss in order to reveal the truth
他是不是想要揭發 時田玻璃破產的真相
hidden behind the bankruptcy of Tokita Glass.
才製造了這場騷動呢？
Mr. Karashima. Can I go to Iwate tomorrow?
辛島部長 我明天可以去一趟岩手嗎？
Iwate?
岩手？
Why would you go so far?
為什麼要去那麼遠的地方？
Mr. Kuga, former senior executive director of Tokita Glass, lives in Iwate now.
時田玻璃過去的專務久我先生 現在住在岩手
You want to see him, and get some information?
妳想去找他問問詳情嗎？
Yes.
是的
Since President Tokita passed away and his son is in hiding,
時田社長去世了 他的兒子又藏匿了起來
he is the only one who knows what happened a year ago.
只有他知道一年前發生了什麼事
Okay. Go to Iwate.
我知道了，你們去吧
But Mr. Karashima…
辛島部長
It's their job to solve problems at the branch.
分行稽核班的職責 就是解決分行的問題
This problem has not been solved yet.
這個問題看來還沒結束呢
Thank you very much.
非常感謝
It's that way.
是那邊
The air is clear.
空氣真清新啊
It's here.
就是這裡
Okay.
嗯
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -是
I am Soma from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我是東京第一銀行的相馬
I would like to meet Mr. Yasuhiko Kuga,
我想見見 曾經擔任時田玻璃專務董事的
who was the senior executive director of Tokita Glass.
久我靖彥先生
That's my husband. He is in the backyard. But…
那是我丈夫，他現在在後院
Is that him?
是他吧？
Hello!
不好意思
You must be Mr. Kuga.
請問您是久我先生吧？
I am Soma from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我們是東京第一銀行的職員 我是相馬
I am Hanasaki.
我是花咲
FORMER SENIOR EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF TOKITA GLASS
（時田玻璃前專務董事）
Why is Tokyo Daiichi Bank here?
東京第一銀行的人怎麼會來？
I would like to know about the bankruptcy of Tokita Glass.
我們想詢問一下 時田玻璃公司破產的事情
Go away.
你們走吧
I have nothing to say.
我跟銀行沒什麼好說的
But Mr. Kuga…
久我先生…
Don't come in here with those shoes.
別穿那種鞋子踩進來！
I'm sorry.
對不起
Damn it.
真是的
The police are looking for Mr. Tsuneo Tokita
豐洲分行發生的縱火事件
as a suspect for the arson attack at Toyosu Branch.
警方已經將時田恒夫列為重要嫌疑人
Could you tell us what happened behind the bankruptcy a year ago?
請你告訴我們 一年前的破產事件背後的真相
I think it's connected to the reason why he planned this attack.
這件事與他製造這起騷亂 應該是有關聯的
Do you know where Mr. Tsuneo Tokita is?
你知道時田恒夫先生在哪嗎？
Even if I did, why would I tell you guys?
就算我知道，為什麼要告訴你們？
You probably want to find Tsuneo before the police catch him
你們一定是想在警察捉到恒夫之前
so that you can stop him from exposing the truth.
找到他，不讓他把真相說出來吧？
-No, we would never do such a thing. -You guys…
-不，我們不會這麼做的 -你們啊
You lie with a straight face.
還能睜眼說瞎話呢
Your bank destroyed the lives of the Tokita family.
你們的銀行毀了時田一家的人生
President Tokita was killed by Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
時田社長就是被東京第一銀行殺害的
What do you mean by that?
這是什麼意思？
Go away. I am busy. Don't disturb me.
滾，我很忙，別打擾我幹活
I'm sorry. He's so stubborn.
對不起啊，他就是那麼固執
No.
別這麼說
Um… may I ask you a favor?
那個…我們想拜託妳一件事
What is it?
什麼事？
Please let me help you.
我們來幫你吧
I knew it.
我就知道會這樣
Should I cut like this?
這個…像這樣切可以嗎？
May I ask you something after this?
等活幹完了 能跟我們談談那件事嗎？
I won't promise you such a thing.
我可不能保證
What if we harvest all the way over there?
如果我們一直收割到那一邊呢？
That's impossible for an amateur.
外行是不可能做到的
But what if we do it?
那如果做到了呢？
You can't do it.
都說了不可能
May I use this?
這個借我一下
It's done.
做完了
Wow! You did a great job.
你們好厲害啊！
We did it!
我們很努力了
Aren't you glad they helped?
他們兩人能幫忙真是太好了
Would you like to have dinner with us?
如果可以的話 你們留下來吃晚飯吧！
Really?
可以嗎？
Enjoy the freshly harvested vegetables.
來嘗嘗自己新鮮收割的蔬菜吧！
Thank you!
-好的！
I never knew that it tastes this good when you harvest it yourself.
沒想到自己收割的蔬菜竟然如此美味
This cutlet is delicious too.
這個肉餅也好好吃啊
It makes me happy to see you enjoying it.
看你們這麼喜歡，我真高興啊
The suspect of the arson attack at Tokyo Daiichi Bank was arrested.
東京第一銀行 縱火事件嫌疑人已被逮捕
They arrested Tsuneo Tokita, an unemployed 21-year-old living in the Koto ward.
嫌疑人時田恒夫居住在江東區 21歲，無業游民
He was arrested under suspicion of setting fire to
他涉嫌在東京第一銀行豐洲分行
Tokyo Daiichi Bank Toyosu Branch by placing alkali metal
將鹼金屬投入提款機區域的垃圾桶裡
in a garbage can near the ATM corner.
引起火災
It has been reported that
根據調查，時田嫌疑人
he admitted to all charges during the questioning.
已承認自己所犯下的罪行
Mr. Kuga…
久我先生
would you please tell us about the details?
你能告訴我們詳情了嗎？
We think that Tsuneo was willing to commit a crime in order to punish
我們認為恒夫他不惜犯下如此罪行
Branch Manager Saegusa because of something
也要懲罰三枝經理
that happened with the bankruptcy.
當初公司破產的背後 一定隱藏著什麼吧？
I don't know if we will be able to do anything.
我們不知道自己能做什麼
But we will not conceal the truth.
但是 我們絕不會讓真相就這樣石沉大海
Um… may I open this?
這個可以看嗎？
Yes.
看吧
TOKITA GLASS CORPORATION
（時田玻璃公司）
Tsuneo didn't know anything until a month ago.
恒夫是一個月前才知道所有事情的
The president told him everything before he died last month.
社長上個月去世之前 把一切都告訴了他
He apologized to Tsuneo for bankrupting the company.
社長為了公司破產的事向恒夫道歉
He said he was deceived by the bank because he was stupid.
說是因為自己笨，才會被銀行騙了
What do you mean he was deceived?
被騙了是什麼意思？
Branch Manager Saegusa is the one that proposed the business expansion
兩年前建議擴大公司業務的人
two years ago.
就是三枝經理
You have a chance at expanding your business overseas
如果你把生產製造的基地移到泰國
if you move your production base to Thailand.
就有機會擴展海外市場 使資產翻倍了
Please think about it.
請務必考慮一下
No. I am not planning to expand my company like that.
不用了 我們公司沒有這樣擴張的打算
We're happy with the size of our company right now.
現在的規模就很好了
I see.
這樣啊
We were planning to decline the offer at first.
我們一開始是拒絕的
Good morning.
早安
It's hot today.
今天真熱啊
May I see the factory?
我能不能參觀一下工廠呢？
But the branch manager came to our company many times to persuade us.
但是，三枝經理 親自來我們公司很多次，說服我們
The president was a nice man, so he felt like he should trust the bank.
社長人太好了 覺得三枝經理是可以信任的
I have decided to take Branch Manager Saegusa's suggestion.
我決定接受你的建議
That's wonderful.
真的嗎？
I'm sure it will go well.
一定會順利的
In the end, he decided to expand the business.
於是，最終決定擴張公司
-Thank you. -Yes.
-謝謝 -是
He got a loan of 1.5 billion yen from the bank.
接受了銀行15億日元的融資
But as we were building the factory…
但就在我們建設工廠期間…
-President. -…Thailand became politically unstable.
-社長 -…泰國政治開始不穩定
Please look at this.
請看看這個
ANTI-GOVERNMENT DEMONSTRATION IN THAILAND JAPANESE BUSINESS SUFFERS
（泰國反政府示威 日本企業受到打擊）
The company had to withdraw while shouldering the loss.
公司必須在虧損的情況下撤退
All of a sudden, we had a huge debt.
一夜之間，公司變得負債纍纍
The cash-flow became tight,
資金流通十分困難
and when our situation became very critical a year ago,
而一年前，情況變得如此嚴峻的時候
Branch Manager Saegusa noticed it right away and visited us.
三枝經理最先察覺到這一點 來造訪我們公司
We need an additional loan,
請幫我們追加融資
or our company will go bankrupt.
不然，我們公司會破產的
Please.
拜託了
Okay.
好的
Really?
真的嗎？
Of course, President Tokita.
當然了，時田社長
But I need to discuss this with headquarters as well.
不過，我必須先向總部請示
In order to do that, will you pay off your loan first?
所以，能不能 請你們先償還融資的餘額？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Don't worry. It is a temporary measure.
請放心，這不過是暫時的
Look here.
我寫給你們看
3.6% - REFINANCE WITH 1%, 2 MILLION, 7 - 12 YEARS
（再融資1% 200萬，7至12年）
Currently you get a loan at an annual interest rate of 3.6%.
你們目前的融資利息是3.6%
If you pay it off in a lump sum, you can obtain a good credit history.
如果你們能一次還清的話 就會獲得良好的信用記錄
Then you will get refinanced
這樣你們就能以1%的利息
with 1% interest.
取得再融資
Yes.
這樣啊
As a result, you can lower the amount you owe
如此一來，你們的欠款就能大大減少
and extend the pay-back period by a considerable amount.
還能延長償還期限呢
Your company will only reap benefits with this deal.
這個交易對貴公司來說 是百利而無一弊的
But it's hard for us
可是
to pay off the entire loan, even if it's temporary.
就算是暫時的 要我們償還全額還是很困難呢
You need to scrape the money together somehow.
那你們只能盡力去湊錢了
It is worth doing.
這是值得的
I understand.
我知道了
President…
社長
This is the only way for you to save your company.
這是拯救公司的唯一方法了
I understand. I will prepare the money.
我知道了，我會想辦法湊錢的
He ran around borrowing money,
社長東奔西走，到處借錢
and even gathered his personal and family assets together.
甚至抵押了自己和家人的個人資產
He somehow gathered enough to pay off
總算湊齊了錢
the entire loan.
償還貸款的全額
However…
然而…
He couldn't get the additional loan.
到頭來，還是無法獲得融資吧？
Please wait.
等等，三枝經理
That's not what you promised.
這跟你說的不一樣
You said that if I paid off my loan,
你明明說只要我還清了全額
you would help me refinance with a better rate.
你就會幫我以優惠的利息再次融資的
I didn't promise you such a thing.
我可沒說過這種話
What?
什麼？
What you're talking about
剛才你所說的
is called
是貸款承諾
"loan commitment" and it's something a banker should never promise.
這是銀行職員絕對不能信口承諾的 更何況，我是分行經理呢
No way…
怎麼會這樣？
Our bank collected the money that we had loaned. That's all.
我們銀行已經回收了融資，僅此而已
Branch Manager. You deceived us?
三枝經理，你欺騙了我們嗎？
Stop accusing me of such a thing.
請別說這種侮辱我的話
How dare you?
你好過分啊！
Our company declined because of the business expansion last year.
我們公司是因為去年的擴張才出事的
You advised me to do so.
勸我們擴張公司的不就是你嗎？
You're blaming others because you failed?
失敗了就把責任推到別人身上嗎？
You are the one that ruined your company.
毀掉公司的人是你
-Please wait. -President.
-等等！ -社長…
Please, Branch Manager Saegusa!
拜託了，三枝經理
I am begging you.
我求求您了
Please help us.
您幫幫我們吧…
President Tokita, you're finished.
時田社長，你已經完了
President! Are you okay?
社長，你沒事吧？
Soon after, Tokita Glass couldn't keep up with the payments and went bankrupt.
之後，沒過多久 時田玻璃再也沒能力支付，就破產了
Banks…
銀行啊
lend an umbrella when it's sunny
晴天借傘
and take it away
雨天呢
when it is raining.
就收傘
They forced a loan on us
我們公司業績良好
when our business was good and didn't require financing.
也沒有財務需求的時候 他們就來強迫我們融資
But when our performance went bad, they forced us to pay it back
等到我們業績變差 就絲毫不考慮我們公司的情況
without showing us any consideration.
逼我們還錢
Hey…
我問你們
is that what your bank does?
這就是你們銀行的做法嗎？
No…
不是的
That is…
這麼做…
so wrong.
是不對的
It is definitely wrong.
這麼做絕對是大錯特錯
They were able to collect the loan from Tokita Glass
他們能全額回收時田玻璃的融資
because Branch Manager Saegusa used a dirty trick.
都是因為三枝經理使用了卑鄙的手段
Yes.
是啊
On paper, it just shows that Tokita Glass paid it off by themselves.
可是，檔案上也只會記錄成 時田玻璃主動還款
The branch manager won't be penalized for this?
三枝經理就無需為此負責嗎？
Promising a loan, is called "loan commitment"
跟對方約定一定會給予融資
and it's something a banker should never do.
被稱為貸款承諾 是銀行職員絕不能做的事
Right.
是啊
But he just made a verbal promise.
但他只是口頭上承諾了
There is no signed promise nor was it recorded.
並沒有交換字據或是錄音之類的
There is no evidence.
沒有證據啊
That's why President Tokita couldn't do anything but give up.
所以時田社長也只能忍氣吞聲
There is a customer experiencing so much pain just because of one banker.
我們的客戶因為一個銀行職員 經歷了那麼多痛苦
It's so unfair that we can't do anything about it.
我們卻什麼也做不了，這太不公平了
I know what you are saying.
確實很不公平
Isn't this the piece of paper
相馬，這不就是
that Mr. Saegusa used to explain the refinancing plan?
三枝經理說明再融資時的記錄嗎？
Yes, you are right.
對，是的
Can we use it as evidence?
這個可以當作證據嗎？
No, this is too weak.
不，這還不夠呢
Huh? Give it to me, Hanasaki.
咦？花咲，借我看一下
This could be evidence.
這個說不定能成為證據哦
Look here.
妳看這個
I am very sorry to have caused you trouble with this case.
很抱歉這次給各位添麻煩了
I am relieved the suspect was arrested so quickly.
那麼快就逮捕了嫌犯，真是太好了
But this experience has taught me that
但這次我們銀行
we can be harmed even though we have nothing to be blamed for.
在沒犯下什麼錯的情況下遭遇這件事 真是讓我感觸良多啊
This was a case of unjustified resentment.
這次只是一宗毫無原因的怨恨案例
But please be careful so that this never happens again.
不過，今後你也得多加注意 避免再次發生
Yes, I will.
是
Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常務
I want to confirm something.
我想確認一件事
Yes?
什麼事？
Come in!
進來吧
-Excuse me.
-打擾了
Why is Branch Inspection here?
分行稽核班怎麼會來？
They'd like to reveal some new information regarding Tokita Glass.
他們發現了一些有關時田玻璃的事情
May we?
我們可以說嗎？
What is it?
什麼事？
Branch Manager Saegusa.
三枝經理
You offered a loan of 1.5 billion yen to Tokita Glass two years ago
你在兩年前 給時田玻璃提供了15億的融資
and advised them to expand their business.
勸說他們擴張公司
But it failed.
但他們失敗了
I didn't force them to do so.
我並沒有強迫他們
They agreed to do so.
是對方自己也同意的
But once you knew that Tokita Glass was in serious financial trouble,
但是，當你發現 時田玻璃陷入了嚴重的財務困境
you tried to collect the loan by force.
卻強行回收了融資
Is there something wrong with trying to recover a loan?
只是試圖回收融資而已，這有錯嗎？
No.
沒錯
There's no problem with that. On paper, that is.
根據檔案上的記錄來看 這沒什麼問題
But the way you went about it, was wrong.
但你的做法依然是錯的
This is the evidence to prove that.
證據就在這裡
I borrowed this from the former senior executive director of Tokita Glass.
這是我們從時田玻璃的 前任專務董事那裡拿來的
This is a memo promising that he would refinance them
這是你在答應他們 如果能全額償還融資款項
at a better rate if they
就會以更優惠的利息
paid off their loan first.
給予他們再融資時寫下的
You deceived President Tokita
你用了貸款承諾這個手段
by using a method called a "loan commitment."
欺騙了時田玻璃的社長
I didn't write that.
我沒寫過那種東西
No,
不
you did write this, Branch Manager Saegusa.
這就是你寫下的，三枝經理
This is the basis for that claim.
而證明這點的是這個
All documents printed from computers within our bank
使用我們銀行內部的電腦 打印出來的所有文件上
have an identification code like this.
都會有這一行識別代碼
This code can track when the document was printed out,
這個代碼可以告訴我們是在什麼時候
from which computer, and by whom.
被誰用哪一台電腦打印出來的
You should know this, of course.
這點你應該知道吧？
So we asked the System Department.
我們剛才問過系統部了
-Please check this code. -Okay.
-麻煩你查一下這個代碼 -好的
This document was printed out by Branch Manager Saegusa.
這份資料正是由三枝經理打印出來的
If you disagree,
如果你還是否認的話
we can take it to an appropriate agency for a handwriting analysis.
我們可以委託專業機構進行筆跡鑒定
All I did was recover the loan for the sake of our bank.
我是為了銀行，才回收融資的
What's wrong with that?
這有什麼問題？
I might have been a little aggressive.
也許這個手段有點偏激
But that company was done with
但無論我有沒有強硬回收
whether I collected the money or not.
那家公司都會完蛋的
It is so annoying that you're bringing up an old loan that ended over a year ago.
都一年前的事了，還拿出來說 你們怎麼那麼煩呢？
It's over.
都過去了
With all due respect…
恕我直言
it isn't over yet.
這件事還沒結束
What isn't over yet?
什麼意思？
The lives of the people who used to work for Tokita Glass.
我是說時田玻璃的員工的人生
What?
什麼？
You pushed a loan on them when their business was good
他們業績好的時候 你硬是要人家進行融資
but forced it back when their business went down.
業績不好了就強迫還款
Do loans only exist for the selfish benefit and profit of the bank?
難道融資只是為了 這麼自私的銀行利益才存在的嗎？
You don't understand anything.
妳真是什麼都不懂呢
The bank is…
在銀行這個地方…
Putting the bank first won't justify all your actions.
為了銀行就可以不擇手段了嗎？
-You are so arrogant. Shut up! -No, I won't!
-妳真放肆啊，閉嘴！ -我不要！
What you did robbed people of their livelihood.
你的所作所為奪走了那些人的生活
But their lives have continued on.
但他們的人生仍在繼續
So don't you dare say that it's all over.
所以，請你別說這事已經結束了
Lend an umbrella when it is sunny
晴天借傘
and take it away when it rains.
雨天收傘
Branch Manager Saegusa, you just bullied the weak.
你那樣做不過是欺負弱者罷了
That's definitely wrong!
那是大錯特錯
I did nothing wrong.
我沒有…做錯
I… I…
我…
Mr. Saegusa.
三枝
Yes, Executive Director Shindo.
是，真藤常務
You…
你啊
did a wrong thing.
確實是做錯了
I heard that you will bring in Saegusa to be questioned
聽說三枝的事
by the inquiry commission.
你交給調查委員會了
Yes.
是的
You're okay with that? He was in your faction.
可以嗎？他可是你的派系的
No problem.
沒問題
I'm not so weak as to sway over a small matter such as this.
我不至於弱到 因為這點程度的事就動搖
I see.
這樣啊
You are a stronger rival than I thought.
看來，你是比我想像還強勁的對手啊
Thank you.
過獎了
Yes. I will be happy to visit.
好，我一定會去拜訪的
Okay. We'll be waiting for you.
那我們就等著妳來了
My wife wants to see you too.
我老婆也很期待見到妳呢
Please say hello to Mr. Soma.
對了，請替我們向相馬先生問好
Yes, I will. See you then.
我會的，再見
What did Mr. Kuga say?
久我先生說什麼了？
He said he will be a guarantor for Mr. Tsuneo Tokita.
他說他做了時田恒夫的擔保人
I see.
這樣啊
What kind of sentence will he receive?
他會受到什麼判決呢？
I'm sure they will take his situation into consideration.
我相信他們會酌情辦理的
I don't think he'll get a heavy penalty.
應該會獲得輕判吧
You're right.
應該吧
Guess what Mr. Kuga said?
你知不知道久我先生說什麼？
He said, "I wish I had met bankers like you a lot sooner."
他說：“如果能早點遇到 像你們這樣的銀行職員就好了”
-Oh, really? -Yes.
-是嗎？ -是的
Mr. Soma, I will work hard.
相馬，我會繼續加油的
I gained a little courage.
感覺多了一點勇氣呢
I think both Mr. Kuga
我想，久我先生
and Executive Director Shindo changed a little bit.
還有真藤常務都改變了那麼一點點
Maybe I can make some changes if I work even harder.
要是我再加把勁 說不定就能改變什麼了
So I will keep a positive attitude.
所以 我會一直保持這樣積極的態度的
-Hanasaki. -Yes.
-花咲 -是
Don't work hard.
不要加油啦
Huh?
什麼？
It's nice to be positive.
積極是好的
But nothing good happens when you work too hard.
但妳每次加油過了頭 都不會帶來什麼好事
That's not true.
才不是這樣呢
Yes, it is. Yes. Definitely yes.
是這樣的，絕對是
-No. -Yes.
-不是 -就是
-No! -Yes!
-不是… -就是…
Kuranaka Kensetsu?
藏中建設？
Yes. There is a rumor that they will go bankrupt soon.
是的，有傳聞說他們有破產的可能
We gave a substantial loan to that company.
我們銀行也給了他們一筆巨額融資
It will be a problem if they go bankrupt.
如果真的破產的話，就麻煩了
Hopefully it's just a rumor.
希望只是傳聞
Excuse me.
那我先出去了
Kuranaka Kensetsu…
藏中建設啊
Executive Director Shindo accepted a bribe?
真藤常務收受賄賂？
Are you admitting that it happened?
你承認剛才說的是事實嗎？
This bank is finished.
這家銀行真的是完蛋了
Why did you do it?
你為什麼要這麼做？
Enough. Shut up.
夠了，閉嘴！
Let's go find the 100 million yen.
我們去找那一億日元的下落吧
You're saying that you still want to protect this bank?
即使是這樣的銀行，你也想守護嗎？